Omkar Borle

Sound understanding and Experience in the Digital / Online Domain with a Business Management Degree in Marketing

Who I Am

A Digital evangelist with over 6 years of experience, have helped manage several brands in the digital space from FMCG, BFSI, Automobile to B2B over the past 6 years. The brands managed included Fiat India, Aditya Birla, HDFC, Colgate Palmolive, LIC India, Logitech, Hafele, Richfeel, Brand Capital (Times Group), L&T Finance and many more. With an opportunity to work with some of the best agencies in the country viz. id8labs, JWT, Quasar (Group M), I have developed a sound understanding of all digital platforms including Web, Social, Search, Media & Mobile. A self-confessed fitness freak and a die-hard metal fan, I am a teetotaler and prefer to relax on weekends, and listen to rock music.

Professional Experience

Head- Planning & Strategy, IdeateLabs (Ionz Digital)

Mumbai (October 2011 till date)

- → Responsible for all strategy and planning for every project within the company.
- → Providing strategic and comprehensive solutions on the digital medium, across all platforms, from media, Social media, Google creative Mobile or technology.
- → Leading a team of 12 people across Servicing, Social & Search teams. Responsible for their KRAs, and ensuring smooth functioning and deliveries.
- → Providing quarterly targets to the CS team, to ensure growth.
- → Initiating new businesses and taking it towards closure.
- → Identifying new opportunities and providing valuable and lucrative opportunities.
- → Pitch the company's offerings and capabilities to prospective clients.
- → Develop and implement strategies for prospective clients.

Clients Managed: Richfeel, Brand Capital (Times Group), Sanofi, Logitech, Hafele, L&T Financial Services, Religare Mutual Fund, Axis Bank

*Won the employee of the year award 2013-2014

Account Manager, Quasar Media (Group M)

Mumbai (April 2011 to Sept 2011)

- → Complete responsibility of managing Colgate Palmolive across 5 brands.
- → Ideating & managing campaigns across Digital, Social & Mobile.
- → Extending offline initiatives to digital & maximizing results.
- → Increasing existing revenues to the given targets.

Sr. Executive, JWT Digital

Mumbai (Oct 2010 to April 2011)

- → Develop and implement strategies for prospective clients
- → Developing Digital and social media strategies
- → Closing the proposition made to the client by providing timely suggestions and recommendations

Clients Managed: LIC of India, Godrej GoJiyo, FedEx

Asst. Manager, Client Acquisitions, id8labs (IMACS)

Mumbai (October 2010 – September 2011)

- → Digital Strategies, Managing Online Campaigns, Social Media, Search
- → Identify and develop business opportunities
- → Pitch the company's offerings and capabilities to prospective clients.
- → Develop and implement strategies for prospective clients
- → Closing the proposition made to the client by providing timely suggestions and recommendations.

Clients Managed: Carlsberg, Disney, Axis Bank

Asst. Manager, Client Servicing, id8labs (IMACS)

Mumbai (January 2010 - October 2010)

- → Web site development, Managing Online Campaigns, Social Media, Search
- → To delineate and execute marketing plans for web marketing collaterals such as the corporate landing page and web campaigns for clients from various industries including finance, retail, automobiles etc.
- → To apply digital media marketing strategies for developing successful client websites and web campaigns to increase their website ROI.
- → To apply digital media marketing strategies for developing successful client websites and web campaigns to increase their website ROI.
- → Strategies means and methods to improve traffic to the client website.

Clients Managed: Aditya Birla Financial Services, Fiat India, HDFC Bank.

Executive, Client Servicing, id8labs (IMACS)

Mumbai (May 2009 - January 2010)

- → Executing the website objectives as suggested to the clients to achieve their objectives.
- → Coordinating the online media activities internally as well as with the clients.
- → Executing the website development plan and maintenance post development.

<u>Media Planning & Buying</u>, Unisource Group(Steve & Barrys University Sportswear)

Mumbai (Nov 2006 - Aug 2007)

- → Researching various TG and markets in US
- → Researching & Selecting the right media vehicle.
- → Developing an effective media plan to achieve the marketing objectives.

Educational Qualifications

→ Post Graduation Diploma in Business Management 2007-09

K.J. Somaiya Institute of Management Studies, Mumbai

→ B.Sc.IT, 2003 - 2005

Bhavan's college Andheri, Mumbai

→ HSC, 2000 - 2003

Bhavan's college Andheri, Mumbai

Why I'm Different

Learn.Implement.Improvise

- → I am an antithesis of an angry, temperamental and serious 'Head'. I am a prankster, a friend and yet thorough, with what I do when it comes to work.
- → I believe in 'change' and adapt to it quiet easily. It just adds in today's digital world, because it is changing everyday.
- → Being a quick learner and keen eye to detailing which comes naturally to me makes work easier and interesting to me

What I Can Contribute

- → Apart from just digital knowledge, I posses technical and creative understanding. Creative understanding comes to me naturally, which is always a strong point.
- → Being in an agency, it is imperative to have a fair know-how of all the other mediums, and I do have a fair understanding of both, technology and creative.
- → Being on the agency side, and having worked on multiple projects and brands, we need to get into understanding a brand inside out. Additionally being in strategy and planning it gives better insight towards not only the brand but also the competitors.
- → Thus I believe I can give a direction to a brand on the digital medium thereby increasing the ROI indirectly.